<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[PolarBill's blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Random things I've found interesting.]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 19:14:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.polarbill.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Inspecting and correlating TLS/SSL traffic in Windows]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>With the final deadline looming for PCI systems to use only TLS 1.2 (OK they allow better 1.1, but suggest you use ony 1.2 if possible), We had a few clients who were still using TLS 1.0. Enforcing just TLS 1.2 is easy, but not always the case if you still want all of your custom windows applications to still work. To this I started to use Microsoft Message Analzer to not just see what TLS/SSL protocols were being used, but also what processes were obstinently still using the older cipher suites.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I would like to preface that this is not the best way to run to preliminarily look for older SSL/TLS in your environment. If you just want to see what versions of TLS, but dont really care about finding the process, then you will have a much easier time running wireshark or seeing if your FW can detect ther version. Using tcpdump or Wireshark capture filter of "tcp port 443 and (tcp[((tcp[12] &amp; 0xf0) &gt;&gt; 2)] = 0x16)" will limit to TLS handshake traffic and is much easier to run for longer periods of time. Additionally Microsoft Message Analyzer requires A LOT of resources to parse a 250 mg trace. I would suggest 4 cores and 16 gigs of ram, and you should still expect to give the tool 30-60 seconds when loading or making major changes. I tried running MMA in my Azure instance (Standard D1: 1 core, 3.5 gigs ram) and I gave up after it spiked the CPU for 11 hours.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What MMA does have going for itself are two things. Being able to associate traffic with a process, and being able to natively capture traffic with installing any software on the server. This is a bonus in my use case as a change request process for PCI envrionments could delay troubleshooting.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Alright, lets dive into using this tool. Install MMA on a system you with plenty of CPU and moderate RAM. I would recommend not installing it on the server you want to investigate. Through MMA, you can run a remote trace if you have the right firewall rules in place, but I normally set up capturing the packets as a separate process.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On the system you want to investigate. Run an elevated command prompt. Then start the packet capture by typing <strong>netsh trace start capture=yes</strong>. This will start the trace and save to appdata\local\temp\NetTraces\ and default to a capture size of 250 MB. This can be changes by adding <strong>tracefile=(drive location)\(file name).etl</strong> and change the max file size by adding <strong>maxsize=###mb</strong>(warning, extending the size  larger will tax MMA proportionally). The trace file will start and start capturing a lot of data. Depending on the amount of traffic in your environment, you can max the trace file rather quickly.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>While we are waiting for the capture, lets make some changes to assist us win analysis in MMA. We are going to add aliases for expected IP addresses. This will let us see a nickname instead of the IP address. Well start the first view of MMA.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA.PNG" alt="MMA.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Then Click on Tools &gt; Aliases &gt; Manage Aliases</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-aliases_1.PNG" alt="MMA aliases 1.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I haven&#8217;t found a way to start a brand new alias (small gripe), so right-click on the loopback address and select "Create a Copy"</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-aliases_2.PNG" alt="MMA aliases 2.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Next Change the IP value to what you expect and give it the nickname you want. For this demo I only created the local IP and a gateway IP. In reality you would create aliases for the connections you expect the server will have. You&#8217;ll also need to go and check mark the alias you want MMA to enable.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-aliases_3.PNG" alt="MMA aliases 3.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Once you&#8217;ve waited an appropriate time, go back to the server and run <strong>netsh trace stop</strong>.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/netsh_trace.PNG" alt="netsh trace.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This will finish collecting data and once done provide two files. The primary .etl file mentioned in the output and a .cab file named the same way. Copy these two files to your local machine, load them in MMA and take a abreak. Wait till your cpu utilization stays below 80%, and expect MMA to take nearly 2 gigs of ram per trace you have loaded. Now we are ready to start investigating. Below is a picture of a newly loaded session.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-loaded.PNG" alt="MMA loaded.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Now we&#8217;ll add some filters and additional columns to make our job quicker. First we&#8217;ll have MMA show just TLS/SSL traffic of any version. The best filter is <strong>(TLS.records[0].version)</strong>, however if you are looking for specific versions, you can also do <strong>(TLS.records[0].version) and (TLS.records[0].version.minor == 0)</strong> for SSL 3.0 or use <strong>(TLS.records[0].version) and (TLS.records[0].version.minor != 3)</strong> for all non-TLS 1.2 traffic. Refer to the table below for information on specifics.</p>
</div>
<table class="tableblock frame-topbot grid-all" style="width: 80%;">
<colgroup>
<col style="width: 33.3333%;">
<col style="width: 33.3333%;">
<col style="width: 33.3334%;">
</colgroup>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-right valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><strong>Common Version name</strong></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-center valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><code>Response Major version</code></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><em>Response Minor version</em></p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-right valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><strong>SSL 3.0</strong></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-center valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><code>03</code></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><em>00</em></p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-right valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><strong>TLS 1.0</strong></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-center valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><code>03</code></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><em>01</em></p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-right valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><strong>TLS 1.1</strong></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-center valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><code>03</code></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><em>02</em></p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-right valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><strong>TLS 1.2</strong></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-center valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><code>03</code></p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock"><em>03</em></p></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Once you hit Apply on the filter, you should only see TLS traffic,</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-filter.PNG" alt="MMA filter.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because Module column will be just TLS and the Summary column wont caontain valuable data, we&#8217;ll go ahead and shorten the widths. I&#8217;ll then click on one of the "messages", Select IPv4 layer on the lower left window (Messsage Stack 1). Then right-click on the Source and Destination address in the "Details 1" window. And select "Add Source/Destination Address as Column". You&#8217;ll see MMA might also run recursive DNS. Then I&#8217;ll click on the TLS layer in "Message Stack 1", expand Records in "Details 1" and expand [0]. Now we will add version as a Column as well.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-add_columns.PNG" alt="MMA add columns.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Everything up to now can be done in Wireshark, a tool I prefer over MMA almost every time. Now lets add process details. On the upper right is another window called "Field chooser". In its search bar, lets type <strong>process</strong>. You should see high up in the list will include, Process Command, Process ID, Process Name, and Process User SID under Global Properties.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-filed_chooser.PNG" alt="MMA filed chooser.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I like to add the Process Name and Process Command. Once you&#8217;ve add these, you&#8217;ll notice that the ProcessName might include "Idle" or a "(<mark>#</mark>)". You&#8217;ll see idle when a packet is inbound to the system. Considering the nature of SSL/TLS, you can ignore these and filter them out if you would like.
I have seen it sometimes also provides a false process as well for inbound packets. The the ProcessName field has a number in parentheses, then that is the process ID and the process ended before stopping the packet capture. If you have the proper auditing, then you can cross reference event logs for the process ID.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the picture below, you can see two processes highlighted. WindowsAzureGuestAgent using TLS 1.2 and LF Intrusion Detection Service using TLS 1.0. At this point, I would confirm that tool has the capability to use TLS 1.2 and then research the proper solution.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://blog.polarbill.com/images/2018-04_PCI-MMA/MMA-2processes.PNG" alt="MMA 2processes.PNG">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Last thing I want to make you aware is if you are looking into an external facing IIS (w3wp.exe) or other website that is using TLs. Be aware that the external client might not be able to use TLS 1.2. In those situations, it helps to review the initial TLS handshake where you can see the client and server repsonses that includes what version they want to use to communicate.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com/2018/04/09/MMA-might-save-the-day.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.polarbill.com/2018/04/09/MMA-might-save-the-day.html</guid><category><![CDATA[PCI]]></category><category><![CDATA[netsh]]></category><category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category><category><![CDATA[Microsoft Message Analyzer]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Watermelon Shark]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Although this is something I made on a whim, I&#8217;m still proud of it and will include it in my colelction of art. More pictures below.</p>
</div>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CgBqHRPgDeA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
<table class="tableblock frame-all grid-all">
<colgroup>
<col>
<col>
</colgroup>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Title</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Watermelon Shark</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Medium</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Food (Watermlon)</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Embedded NFC Serial</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">None</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Provenance</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Bill Davison (2017)<br>
Given to the Martinez family shortly after<br>
Trash can some point after that.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Inspiration</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">The original goal was for this to be made for a pool/movie birthday party where we would watch Jaws in the pool. Time, resources, and weather cause the delay of the shark, but not the party itself. I decided to make it the following week for another party.</p></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="/images/Watermelon_shark_large.jpg" alt="Watermelon shark large.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="/images/Watermelon_shark_front_large.jpg" alt="Watermelon shark front large.jpg">
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com/2017/06/20/Watermelon-Shark.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.polarbill.com/2017/06/20/Watermelon-Shark.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Art]]></category><category><![CDATA[Summer]]></category><category><![CDATA[Watermelon]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Florida Boxer Rescue]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://www.flbr.org">Florida Boxer Rescue</a> posted a "Giving Thanks" <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Florida.Boxer.Rescue">Facebook</a> post on my wife and I. I thought I would add it to my blog.</p>
</div>
<div id="fb-root"></div><script>(function(d, s, id) {  var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];  if (d.getElementById(id)) return;  js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id;  js.src = "//connect.facebook.net/en_US/sdk.js#xfbml=1&version=v2.3";  fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs);}(document, 'script', 'facebook-jssdk'));</script><div class="fb-post" data-href="https://www.facebook.com/Florida.Boxer.Rescue/posts/10153294016860949:0" data-width="500"><div class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore"><blockquote cite="https://www.facebook.com/Florida.Boxer.Rescue/posts/10153294016860949:0"><p>GIVING THANKS!Today we would like to give thanks to Andrea and Bill Davison who are amazing volunteers and foster home...</p>Posted by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Florida.Boxer.Rescue/">Florida Boxer Rescue</a> on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/Florida.Boxer.Rescue/posts/10153294016860949:0">Friday, December 18, 2015</a></blockquote></div></div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For those blocking scripts/cant see it, the pic/text is below.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://scontent-atl3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpt1/v/t1.0-9/s720x720/12348051_10153294016860949_2519079840824693331_n.jpg?oh=f65ccf4324fdc7e675b547a50d5b4f8d&oe=56D9718D" alt="Andrea and myself with Zoey(left and Narley(right)">
</div>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>GIVING THANKS!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today we would like to give thanks to Andrea and Bill Davison who are amazing volunteers and foster home to many dogs in need.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Andrea and Bill Davison have been with the rescue for close to 5 years. They initially applied to FBR to adopt but was asked if they would be willing to foster an urgent needs dog. They immediately stepped up and picked up a &gt;terrified pup from HCAS who they named Chance. Since then, they have been dedicated foster parents to 14 boxers (and counting) and are always willing to volunteer their time at events and FBR gatherings.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Thank you so much for your dedication and willingness to open your heart and home to foster so many dogs in need. Compassionate Care boy Narley has been so blessed to have you for his family and Zoey is loving being with you. Thank you from all of us here at Florida Boxer Rescue. We wouldn&#8217;t be able to save those that we do without volunteers like you!</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/12/19/Florida-Boxer-Rescue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/12/19/Florida-Boxer-Rescue.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Boxer]]></category><category><![CDATA[Dogs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[BSides Las Vegas 2015]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was lucky enough to go to hacker mecha. For me this included the "OG" BSides in Las Vegas. I have attended/volunteered at every BSides Tampa and Orlando, and Las Vegas had the same feeling. People were open for conversation, and it felt like a place to freely meet people and exchange ideas.<br></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This year I took the extra step and decided to present. One amazing part of the Las Vegas BSides (and some others) is that they offer a newbie track (formally called the Proving Ground track.) There is a seperate earlier CFP submission process, where they pair you up with a mentor to assist in your talk. This was the track I selected because of lack in presentation experience. If anyone is feeling nervious about presenting, I would HIGHLY recommend submitting for Proving Ground. I was paired with my mentor Russel (@tcstoolHax0r) who had experience in my topic of SIEMs. He walked me though all the minor things that wouldn&#8217;t come to mind: slide amount, density, etc and also helped with the flow of my talk while also suggesting areas to expand upon for my talk.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/08/27/B-Sdes-Las-Vegas-2015.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/08/27/B-Sdes-Las-Vegas-2015.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[BSides LV Talk - SIEMple technology]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Below is my talk I previously mentioned about setting up and maintaining a SIEM in your environment. If you would like the slides, additional links, or to download my talk, please go to <a href="https://github.com/polarbill/Presentations/tree/master/BSides%20LV%202015">SIEMple Technology materials</a><br></p>
</div>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K6a_CYKgv6o" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/08/27/B-Sdes-LV-Talk-SIE-Mle-technology.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/08/27/B-Sdes-LV-Talk-SIE-Mle-technology.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>