<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[PolarBill's blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[PolarBill's blog]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 22:16:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.polarbill.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[BSides Las Vegas 2015]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was lucky enough to go to hacker mecha. For me this included the "OG" BSides in Las Vegas. I have attended/volunteered at every BSides Tampa and Orlando, and Las Vegas had the same feeling. People were open for conversation, and it felt like a place to freely meet people and exchange ideas.<br></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This year I took the extra step and decided to present. One amazing part of the Las Vegas BSides (and some others) is that they offer a newbie track (formally called the Proving Ground track.) There is a seperate earlier CFP submission process, where they pair you up with a mentor to assist in your talk. This was the track I selected because of lack in presentation experience. If anyone is feeling nervious about presenting, I would HIGHLY recommend submitting for Proving Ground. I was paired with my mentor Russel (@tcstoolHax0r) who had experience in my topic of SIEMs. He walked me though all the minor things that wouldn&#8217;t come to mind: slide amount, density, etc and also helped with the flow of my talk while also suggesting areas to expand upon for my talk.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/08/27/B-Sdes-Las-Vegas-2015.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.polarbill.com/2015/08/27/B-Sdes-Las-Vegas-2015.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>